Vishal Gophane

Winashree CHS., Plot No D-18, Flat No. B-301 Sector-09, Airoli, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra -400708

06/08/1994

PROFILE

CDAC-certified Software Engineering post-graduate seeking entry-level Software Engineer position.Full Stack Web Development and Programming skills and passion for problem-solving. Committed to continuous learning and contributing to dynamic software development teams.

6 years of project management and sales experience, with a track record of delivering projects on time and within budget.

</> IT SKILLS

- lava
- CSS
- IDE's (Eclipse, Spring Tool Suite, VS code, Visual Studio)
- Agile Methodology
- Unit Testing

- MySQL
- lavaScript
- C#
- SDLC

- HTML
- Spring Boot
- Git &Github
- Debugging and Troubleshooting

SOFT SKILL

- Time Management
- Problem Solving
- Leadership
- Creativity

Communication

EDUCATION

09/2022 - 03/2023

Post Graduate Diploma in Advance Computing.

Center for Development of Advance Computing(CDAC), Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY), Government of India

I successfully completed the course with a Grade of 'A' (84.50%).

Modules Learned:

Object Oriented Programming using Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JDBC, Jquery, JSP, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, MERN Stack, SQL, RDBMS, MySQL, MS. NET MVC, C# Programming, Software Engineering and DevOps, SDLC, AWS, Docker and Kubernetes, Agile Methodology, Software Testing (Selenium) using Eclipse IDE, CICD usnig Jenkins, API testing using Postman. Cloud Architecture, EC2

06/2012 – 06/2016

Bachelor's of Engineering,

Savitribai Phule Pune University 🗗

Completed the course in **Mechanical Engineering with**

First Class With Distinction (67.46%)

Kolkata, India

Pune, India

2011 - 2012

Higher Secondary Education, Maharashtra State Board

Mumbai, India

of Secondary & Higher Secondary Education 2 Completed the 12th with First Class -67 %

2010

Secondary School Certificate, Maharashtra State Board

Mumbai, India

of Secondary & Higher Secondary Education 2 Completed the 10th with First Class with Distinction-

90.18%

PROJECTS

02/2023 -03/2023

Purified Water Inventory and Distribution System,

Post Graduation Project,

Role:Team Leader (Team of 5)

Front End- HTML, CSS, Thymleaf, Jquery

BackEnd-Java EE 8, MySQL

Technology used: Spring Boot, MS Windows IDE used: Spring Tool Suite -version 4.15

- This system is concerned with distribution, purchasing & Inventory Management. This system contains Order details, User details & admin Details.
- This web application will help many small and midscale purified water suppliers/distributors properly manage and grow their businesses.
- Generated Software Requirement Specification and Project Plan .
- Worked on the front end as Well as Backend Part of the Project.
- Developed the Project based on Monolithic architecture using Agile methodology
- Created Use Case, Dataflow ,and Activity Diagram for the Project.

09/2015 -03/2016

Reduction in time for application and removal of Black Japan on

Aerospace raw material, Graduation Project

- Project of the Aerospace Division of Walchandnagar Industries Ltd., Walchandnagar.
- In this project, our main objective is to build equipment that is used to reduce the application of Black Japan on Aerospace Raw Materials, semi-finished components, and assembly.
- The Project involves the Design, Manufacturing, Testing, and Commissioning of the equipment at WIL.
- Technology Used: AutoCAD 2014, CATIA V5 R21.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

01/2018 -06/2022

Sales and Service Engineer,

Demech Chemical Products Pvt.Ltd. 🛮

Job Role-Project Incharge

-Managed all Project Execution related activities of various Major and Minor Projects of Speciality Coatings across India worth more than 1 Crore.

-Worked for projects of Clients Like Indian Oil, Hindustan Petroleum, NTPC, BHEL, Tata Power, Adani Power, ONGC, JSW Steel, and JSW Power.

-Quality Control of the Coating Application, Inventory Management, Project Execution Planning, Manpower Management, Customer Relationship Management.

Pune, Maharashtr a, India

Job Role-Business Development

- -New Lead Generation
- Customer Relationship Management.
- -Sales Report Generation

08/2016 - 12/2017 Project Engineer, Thermin Energy Pvt.Ltd ☑

-Worked on the Design of Waste Heat Recovery Boilers/Air Preheaters/Heat exchangers. Management of Materials required for the various Major and Minor Projects.

-Execution and Commissioning of the Project.

-Worked on Drafting of WHRB Piping & instrumentation diagram, Structural Diagram Air Prer-heater, Economiser using AutoCAD 2015.

-Worked on WHRB Projects of Posco Maharashtra Steel ltd.

CERTIFICATES

- JAVA Programming -Beginner to Master ☑
- The Structured Query Language (SQL) offered by University of Colorado Boulder 🛮
- Introdction to Web Development with HTML,CSS,JAVASCRIPT Course By IBM ☑
- The Complete 2023 Web Development BootCamp by Dr.Angela Yu 🛮

Pune.Maharashtr

a, India

• Relation Database Design offered by University of Colorado Boulder 🛮

AWARDS

12/2009	Best Student Award, Radhikabai Meghe Vidyalaya,Airoli,Navi Mumbai
03/2013	Winner of Singing compitition, College of Engineering, Malegaon, Pune
03/2016	Winner of Technical Paper Presentation, Bharti VIdyapeeth's College of Engineering for Women, Pune A National Level Technical Competition organized by the institute
03/2014	Runner-UP in Robo Race, Vidya Pratishthan's College of Engineering, Baramati, Pune

INTERESTS

Singing

Trecking

Football

DECLARATION

I solemnly declare that the information stated above is true and correct to the best of my belief.

Vishal Bhima Gophane

Navi Mumbai